Now, in here we see that many references to black saints:
Aquí vemos referencia a los santos negros, no?
St. Benedict the Moor, St. Elesbaan of Axum,
San Benedicto, San Elesbán,
Our Lady of Sorrows, St. Roch...
Nuestra Señora de los Dolores, San Roque...
You can notice how in this church, the Rosary of Black People,
Entonces, hay que observar también que
there are many Catholic saints, which are very related
en la Iglesia del Rosario vemos siempre la presencia de varios santos católicos
to syncretic religions of African descent.
que tienen mucha relación con el sincretismo de las religiones de matrices africanas.
For example, St. Roch is syncretized with Obaluaê deity,
Por ejemplo, San Roque, incorporado sincreticamente a Obaluaê
St. Barbara with Iansã deity.
Santa Barbara a Iansã.
St. anne, with Nanã.
Nuestra Señora de Santana fundida sincreticamente a Nanã.
And it's a worship of black saints
Y la devoción de los santos negros, no? ]
which have become symbols of the resistance movements
Que terminaron volviendose símbolos de resistencia
to the population of black slaves.
para el pueblo negro esclavizado.
Here we have St. Benedict, worshiped
San Benedicto
not only by the black brotherhoods
que es un santo de referencia no solo para las hermandades
but also in the Congados, feast-day dramatized celebrations.
pero también para las coronaciones de Reyes.
Here we also have St. George, a very well known saint both to
San Jorge, que es un santo muy presente en el catolicismo popular
popular catholicism and to religions of African descent, such as Umbanda.
y tambien en las religiones de matrices africanas como la Umbanda.